Register of the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies Records, 1939-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
- OFFICE FILE, 1937-1947.
  - Public relations file, 1938-1947
    - Resolutions, 1941-1942
      - Signed endorsement forms, many with correspondence attached
        - Connecticut (Folder 7)
        - Delaware (Box 32., Folder 1)
        - District of Columbia (Folder 2)
        - Florida (Folder 3)
        - Georgia (Folder 4)
        - Idaho (Folder 5)
        - Illinois (Folder 6-9)
        - Illinois (Box 33., Folder 1)
        - Indiana (Folder 2)
        - Iowa (Folder 3)
        - Kansas (Box 34., Folder 1)
        - Kentucky (Folder 2)
        - Louisiana (Folder 3)
        - Maine (Folder 4)
        - Maryland (Folder 5)
        - Massachusetts
        - Massachusetts (Box 35., Folder 1-3)
        - Michigan (Box 36., Folder 1)
        - Minnesota (Folder 2)
        - Mississippi (Folder 3)
        - Missouri (Folder 4)
        - Montana (Folder 5)
        - Nebraska (Folder 6)
        - Nevada (Box 37., Folder 1)
        - New Hampshire (Folder 2)
        - New Jersey (Folder 3)
        - New Mexico (Folder 4)
        - New York (Folder 5-7)
        - North Carolina (Folder 8)
        - North Dakota (Folder 9)
        - Ohio (Box 38., Folder 1-2)
        - Oklahoma (Folder 3)
        - Oregon (Folder 4)
        - Pennsylvania (Box 39., Folder 1-3)
        - Pennsylvania (Box 40., Folder 1)
        - Rhode Island (Folder 2)
        - South Carolina (Folder 3)
        - South Dakota (Folder 4)
        - Tennessee (Folder 5)
        - Texas (Box 41., Folder 1)
        - Utah (Folder 2)
        - Vermont (Folder 3)
        - Virginia (Folder 4)
        - Washington (Folder 5)
        - West Virginia (Folder 6)
        - Wisconsin (Folder 7)
        - Wyoming (Folder 8)
      - Subscriptions
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Kiplinger Washington Letter (Folder 10)
- COMMITTEES, 1939-1945
  - Executive Committee. See also CHAIRMAN'S FILE and MEMBERSHIP FILE
    - Correspondence
      - Form letters (Box 42., Folder 1)
      - MacAlarney, Robert E., re Reader's Digest article by Will Irwin (Folder 2)
    - Lists of members (Folder 3)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1940 May 29-1944 March 24 (Folder 4)
    - Statement in reply to that of the British Ambassador of 1941 March 10 (Folder 5)
  - Local Committees (city or town). Outgoing correspondence to members
    - A - Ah (Folder 6)
    - Ai - Al (Folder 7)
    - Am - Aq (Folder 8)
    - Ar - Az (Folder 9)
    - Baa - Bak (Folder 10)
    - Bal - Baq (Folder 11)
    - Bar - Bas (Folder 12)
    - Bat - Baz (Box 43., Folder 1)
    - Bea - Bel (Folder 2)
    - Bem - Bez (Folder 3)
    - Bia - Bix (Folder 4)
    - Bla - Boo (Folder 5)
    - Bop - Boz (Folder 6)
    - Bp - Bre (Folder 7)
    - Brf - Brz (Folder 8)
    - Bsa - Bz (Box 44., Folder 1)
    - Caa-Can (Folder 2)
    - Cao-Caz (Folder 3)
    - Cba - Chz (Folder 4)
    - Cia - Cla (Folder 5)
    - Clb - Col (Folder 6)
    - Com - Coz (Folder 7)
    - Cpa - Crz (Box 45., Folder 1)
    - Csa - Cz (Folder 2)
    - Daa - Daz (Folder 3)
    - De - Dh (Folder 4)
    - Di - Dn (Folder 5)
    - Do - Dq (Folder 6)
    - Dr - Dz (Folder 7)
    - E - Eh (Folder 8)
    - Ei - Eq (Folder 9)
    - Er - Ez (Box 46., Folder 1)
    - F - Fh (Folder 2)
    - Fi - Fk (Folder 3)
    - Fl - Fq (Folder 4)
    - Fr - Fz (Folder 5)
    - G - Gh (Folder 6)
    - Gi - Gq (Folder 7)
    - Gr - Gz (Box 47., Folder 1)
    - Haa - Ham (Folder 2)
    - Han - Har (Folder 3)
    - Has - Haz (Folder 4)
    - Hba - Hen (Folder 5)
    - Heo - Hez (Folder 6)
    - Hfa - Hnz (Folder 7)
    - Hoa - Hok (Folder 8)
    - Hol - Hon (Box 48., Folder 1)
    - Hoo - Hoz (Folder 2)
    - Hp - Huq (Folder 3)
    - Hur - Hz (Folder 4)
    - Ia - Iv (Folder 5)
    - J - Jh (Folder 6)
    - Ji - Jq (Folder 7)
    - K - Kh (Folder 8)
    - Ki - Kl (Box 49., Folder 1)
    - Km - Kq (Folder 2)
    - Kr - Kz (Folder 3)
    - Laa - Lan (Folder 4)
    - Lao - Laz (Folder 5)
    - Lea - Lee (Folder 6)
    - Lef - Ler (Folder 7)
    - Les - Lez (Folder 8)
    - Lia - Lin (Folder 9)
    - Lio - Loo (Folder 10)
    - Lop - Loz (Folder 11)
    - Lpu - Lz (Box 50., Folder 1)
    - Mc - Mc (Folder 2)
    - Maa - Mad (Folder 3)
    - Mae - Man (Folder 4)
    - Mao - Mar (Folder 5)
    - Mas - May (Folder 6)
    - Me - Mez (Folder 7)
    - Mia - Mil (Folder 8)
    - Mim - Miz (Folder 9)
    - Mo - Mor (Box 51., Folder 1)
    - Mos - Moz (Folder 2)
    - Mpa - Mqz (Folder 3)
    - N - Nh (Folder 4)
    - Ni - Ny (Folder 5)
    - O - Oh (Folder 6)
    - Oi - Oq (Folder 7)
    - Or - Oz (Folder 8)
    - Pa - Paz (Folder 9)
    - Pea - Pez (Box 52., Folder 1)
    - Pf - Pl (Folder 2)
    - Po - Pq (Folder 3)
    - Pr - Pz (Folder 4)
    - Q - Qz (Folder 5)
    - R - Ree (Folder 6)
    - Reg - Rh (Folder 7)
    - Ria - Riz (Folder 8)
    - Roa - Rq (Box 53., Folder 1)
    - Rr - Rz (Folder 2)
    - Saa - Saz (Folder 3)
    - Sca - Schz (Folder 4)
    - Sci - Scur (Folder 5)
    - Sea - Shaz (Folder 6)
    - Shea - Shuz (Folder 7)
    - Si - Sl (Folder 8)
    - Sm (Box 54., Folder 1)
    - Sn - So (Folder 2)
    - Sp - Sq (Folder 3)
    - Sr - Ste (Folder 4)
    - Sti - Stz (Folder 5)
    - Su - Sz (Folder 6)
    - T - Th (Folder 7)
    - Ti - Tq (Folder 8)
    - Tr - Tz (Folder 9)
    - U - Uz (Box 55., Folder 1)
    - V - Vz (Folder 2)
    - Wa - Waz (Folder 3)
    - Wea - Wez (Folder 4)
    - Wh - Whz (Folder 5)
    - Wia - Wiz (Folder 6)
    - Wj - Wq (Box 56., Folder 1)
    - Wr - X (Folder 2)
    - Y - Yz (Folder 3)
    - Z - Zz (Folder 4)
  - National Committee, 1939-1945. See also MEMBERSHIP FILE
    - Contributions
      - Redirected to other relief agencies (Folder 5)
      - Retained for expenses (Folder 6)
      - Returned to sender
        - A - K (Folder 7)
        - L - Z (Folder 8)
      - Sent to the International Red Cross and the American Friends Service Committee (Box 57., Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1945
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Appeals to the NCFSD for aid, 1941-1944 (Folder 3)
      - Expressions of support, 1941-1945. Responses written by Perrin Galpin
        - A - B (Folder 4)
        - C - F (Folder 5)
        - G - L (Folder 6)
        - Gemmer, Robert (Folder 7)
        - Githens, Beverly (Folder 8)
        - Hauge, Thea (Folder 9)
        - M - P (Folder 10)
        - R - Z (Folder 11)
      - Replies to the Committee's April 1943 letter for renewed support for the NCFSD (Box 58., Folder 1)
      - Requests for copies of speeches, program material, methods for sending relief supplies or money to family members or others (Folder 2)
    - Lists of names of members (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda - Interoffice
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Galpin, Perrin (Folder 5)
      - Richmond, Raymond H.
        - Department heads, To all (Folder 6)
        - Horner, Charles F. (Folder 7)
        - Jacob, Betty (Folder 8)
        - Kennedy, Rosalie (Box 59., Folder 1)
        - MacAlarney, Robert Emmet (Folder 2)
    - Motion picture proposal (Folder 3)
    - Personnel files (Folder 4)
    - Statements enunciating policy and program (Folder 5)
- CHAIRMAN'S FILE, 1938-1946.
  Papers of Herbert Hoover
  - Clippings
  - Correspondence. Includes memoranda, reports of meetings, and telephone conversations
    - General (Box 60., Folder 1-3)
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Cables, 1940-1941 (Folder 5)
      - Drafts, holograph. Some typescript letters edited by Hoover (Folder 6)
    - Alphabetical files. Incoming and response
      - A-F (Folder 7)
      - G-L (Box 61., Folder 1)
      - M-R (Folder 2)
      - MacAlarney, Robert E. (Folder 3)
      - Richmond, Raymond S. (Folder 4)
      - S-Z (Folder 5)
    - Chronological files. Incoming and response
      - 1939 September-December (Folder 6)
      - 1940
        - January-March (Folder 7)
        - April-August (Box 62., Folder 1)
        - September-October (Folder 2)
        - November 1-20 (Folder 3)
        - November 21-30 (Folder 4)
        - December 1-10 (Folder 5)
        - December 11-31 (Box 63., Folder 1)
      - 1941
        - January (Folder 2)
        - February (Folder 3)
        - March (Folder 4)
        - April (Box 64., Folder 1)
        - May-August (Folder 2)
        - September-December (Folder 3)
        - December 21. Replies to Hoover's letter of this date regarding present committee policy (Folder 4)
      - 1942-1945 (Box 65., Folder 1)
  - Diaries
    - 1938 February-March - Trip to Finland. Includes itinerary, expenses, invitations (Folder 2)
    - 1939-1943
      - Draft by P. C. Galpin (Folder 3)
      - Note cards showing daily meetings, appointments, other Hoover activities (Folder 4)
  - History of the NCFSD General and other World War II relief projects Statements of purpose and organization (Folder 5)
    - The National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies (Box 66., Folder 1-2)
    - United Distribution Commission for Poland, Inc. (Folder 3)
  - Liquidation files of the NCFSD. Correspondence and memoranda (Folder 4)
  - Reports (Folder 5)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Background material. Pamphlets, clippings (Folder 6)
    - Unidentified statement, n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
    - Statement on campaign to supply food, n.d. Typescript drafts (Folder 8)
    - Statement on change in basis of approach, n.d. Typescript fragments and drafts (Folder 9)
    - Statement on reason for organization of the Commission for Relief in Belgium in 1914, n.d. One holograph draft, two typescript drafts (Folder 10)
    - Statement on refusal of British to open blockade, n.d. Holograph and typescript drafts (Folder 11)
    - Address, Madison Square Garden Mass Meeting for Polish Relief under the auspices of the Polish National Council of New York, New York City, New York, 1940 March 12. Typescript (Folder 12)
    - "Russian Misadventure," Collier's, 1940 April 27. Printed copy (Folder 13)
    - Statement in support of President Roosevelt's stand on defense, 1940 May 17. Typescript (Folder 14)
    - Statement, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1940 August 11. Typescript (Folder 15)
    - "We as Americans ...," 1940 September. Six typescript memoranda, seven corrected proofs, eight drafts and draft fragments, a packet of six typescript and printed items generated by a Rolland Hall Sharp article in The Christian Science Monitor, and one printed copy (Box 67., Folder 1)
    - Press release regarding food for Europe, 1940 October 6. Typescript (Folder 2)
    - Press release on food for the little democracies, 1940 October 7. Typescript (Folder 3)
    - "America and the Famine in the Five Little Democracies," 1940 November 15. Speech, Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, New York. Correspondence, clippings, drafts, two printed copies (Folder 4)
    - "Food and War," The Christian Science Monitor, 1940 November 23. Clipping (Folder 5)
    - "When Winter Comes to Europe," 1940 November 23. Reprint of a Collier's article, "Feed Hungry Europe." Clipping and two printed copies (Folder 6)
    - Press release, 1941 January 29. Two typescript copies (Folder 7)
    - "The March of Hunger in Europe," 1941 February 16. Address, Chicago, Illinois. Two printed copies, typescript copy (Folder 8)
    - Statement on purpose of the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies, 1941 February 18. Two typescript copies (Folder 9)
    - Statement by the Executive Committee of the NCFSD in reply to the statement of the British Ambassador, 1941 March 10. Typescript drafts and one printed copy (Folder 10)
    - "An Experiment in Saving the Lives of 3,000,000 Destitute Adults and Children in Belgium," 1941 March 10. Correspondence and three typescript drafts of a statement (Folder 11)
    - Letter to the editor of The Times, London, 1941 April 12. Holograph draft, three typescript copies, clippings (Folder 12)
    - "Shall We Have Compassion Again?" The American Hebrew, 1941 April 25. Printed copy (Folder 13)
    - "Shall We Feed Europe?" (with Dorothy Canfield Fisher), Christian Herald, 1941 June. Printed copy (Folder 14)
    - "Food for the Hungry," The Classmate, 1941 June 21. Printed copy (Folder 15)
    - "A Call to American Reason," 1941 June 29. Radio address reprinted in the Congressional Record, 1941 June 30. Printed copy (Folder 16)
    - Message to delegates, World's Sunday School Association, Mexico City, Mexico, 1941 July 15. Typescript copy, clipping (Folder 17)
    - "Can Europe's Children Be Saved?" 1941 October 19. Radio address, New York City, New York. Draft, printed copy, reprint (Folder 18)
    - Statement after the bombing of Pearl Harbor, 1941 December 8. Typescript (Folder 19)
    - Statement before the U.S. Senate Committee on Banking and Currency, U.S. Congress, 1941 December 16. Typescript (Folder 20)
    - Letter to National Committee members, 1941 December 17. Typescript (Folder 21)
    - Memoranda, 1942 (Folder 22)
    - "We'll Have to Feed the World Again," Collier's, 1942 November 28 (part one) and December 5 (part two). Correspondence, two printed copies and two reprints (Folder 23)
    - "Feed the Starving Now" (with Hugh Gibson), Collier's, 1943 February 20. Clipping and printed copy (Folder 24)
    - "A Check-up of the Food Front," 1943 June 8. Address, New York City, New York. Printed copy (Folder 25)
    - Memorandum of press conference, Brussels, Belgium, 1946 April 8. Typescript (Folder 26)
- MEMBERSHIP FILE, 1939-1946
  - General
    - General
      - Invitations to join (Box 68., Folder 1)
      - Refusals (Folder 2)
      - Resignations (Folder 3)
      - Rosters and mailing lists (Folder 4-5)
      - Suspensions (Folder 6)
      - Thank you letters (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - A (Box 69., Folder 1-26)
      - B-Bi (Folder 27-73)
      - Bl-By (Box 70., Folder 1-52)
      - Ca (Folder 53-78)
      - Ch-Cu (Box 71., Folder 1-39)
      - D-E (Folder 40-84)
      - F (Box 72., Folder 1-39)
      - G (Folder 40-75)
      - H (Box 73., Folder 1-69)
      - I (Folder 70-75)
      - J (Box 74., Folder 1-24)
      - K (Folder 25-48)
      - L-Le (Folder 49-75)
      - Li-Ly (Box 75., Folder 1-21)
      - Mc-Ma (Folder 22-61)
      - M (Box 76., Folder 1-43)
      - N (Folder 44-59)
      - O (Box 77., Folder 1-16)
      - P (Folder 17-60)
      - R (Box 78., Folder 1-41)
      - S-Sh (Folder 42-72)
      - Si-Sz (Box 79., Folder 1-56)
      - Ta-Ti (Folder 57-70)
      - T (Box 80., Folder 1-9)
      - U (Folder 10)
      - V (Folder 11-15)
      - Wa-Wh (Folder 16-49)
      - Wi-Wr (Box 81., Folder 1-21)
      - Y (Folder 22-26)
  - Davis, Norman. Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 82., Folder 1-2)
  - Garrette, Eve, 1939-1945
    - Biography (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence. Includes correspondence of Women Writers Division and printed matter
      - General
        - A (Folder 4)
        - B (Folder 5)
        - C (Folder 6)
        - D (Folder 7)
        - E (Folder 8)
        - F (Folder 9)
        - G (Folder 10)
        - H (Folder 11)
        - I (Folder 12)
        - J (Folder 13)
        - K (Box 83., Folder 1)
        - L (Folder 2)
        - Mc (Folder 3)
        - M (Folder 4)
        - N (Folder 5)
        - O (Folder 6)
        - P (Folder 7)
        - R (Folder 8)
        - S (Folder 9)
        - T-V (Folder 10)
        - W-Z (Folder 11)
      - Authors and writers (Folder 12-13)
    - Expense account (Box 84., Folder 1)
    - Form letters, invitations to join, sample petition (Folder 2)
    - Maps of food distribution in Europe (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda
      - General
        - Incoming (Folder 4)
        - Outgoing (Folder 5)
      - Aydelott, George. Incoming (Folder 6)
    - Publications
      - Agricultural
        - Correspondence (Folder 7)
        - Form letters (Folder 8)
        - Lists of publications (Folder 9)
      - Religious
        - Clippings (Folder 10-12)
        - Contact letter (Folder 13)
        - Correspondence
          - General (Box 85., Folder 1-7)
          - Catholic (Box 86., Folder 1-2)
          - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America (Folder 3)
          - Jewish (Folder 4)
        - Lists
          - General (Folder 5-6)
          - Catholic (Folder 7)
          - Jewish (Folder 8)
        - Subscriptions (Folder 9)
    - Speeches and writings
      - Articles
        - General. Background and publicity material produced by NCFSD (Folder 10-11)
        - Garrette, Eve (Box 87., Folder 1-4)
      - Clippings and typed excerpts from miscellaneous publications re food situation in Europe (Folder 5)
      - Editorials (Folder 6)
      - Poetry
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Correspondence (Folder 8)
      - Radio programs (Folder 9)
      - Report, "Summation of Bigwood Report Comments" (Folder 10)
    - Subject File - Women Writers Division
      - Correspondence and articles offered for publication
        - Baldwin, Faith (Box 88., Folder 1)
        - Booth, Alice (Folder 2)
        - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield (Folder 3)
        - Irwin, Inez Haynes (Folder 4)
        - Lane, Rose Wilder (Folder 5)
        - Mitchell, Ruth Comfort (Folder 6)
        - Ostenso, Martha (Folder 7)
        - Sangster, Margaret (Folder 8)
      - Form letter offering articles for publication (Folder 9)
      - Lists of authoresses and prominent American women (Folder 10)
      - Women's statement (Folder 11)
    - Miscellany (Folder 12)
  - Gibson, Hugh, 1940-1945
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General. Includes printed matter
          - 1940 March-July (Folder 13-15)
          - 1941
            - Jan.-March (Folder 16-17)
            - April-June (Box 89., Folder 1-2)
            - July-Dec. (Folder 3-4)
          - 1942 March-1943 April (Folder 5-6)
          - 1943 April (Folder 7)
          - 1943 May-1945 April (Box 90., Folder 1-3)
        - Galpin, Perrin (Folder 4)
        - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 5)
        - National Committee members (Folder 6)
        - Rickard, Edgar (Folder 7)
        - Tuck, W. Hallam (Folder 8)
      - Cables
        - General
          - Incoming
            - 1940 (Box 91., Folder 1)
            - 1941 (Folder 2)
          - Outgoing (Folder 3)
        - Pate, Maurice (Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1940 June. Typescript (Folder 5)
    - Financial statements and expense accounts, 1940-1945 (Folder 6)
    - Writings. "Food Is a Weapon," 1942 February (Folder 7)
  - Hartigan, John, 1940-1941
    - Biographical material (Folder 8)
    - Clippings (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General. Mostly about Hartigan (Folder 10)
        - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 11)
      - Cables exchanged with "Foodcomm," "Polish Committee" and "Belgamcomm" (Folder 12-14)
    - Speeches and writings
      - Radio interview, NBC, 1940 August (Folder 15)
      - Report on visit to Norway (Folder 16)
  - Horner, Charles, 1939-1944
    - Bulletins and press releases (Box 92., Folder 1)
    - Clippings (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - Form letters and petitions (Folder 3)
        - Sample letters (Folder 4)
      - Allen, Ben (Folder 5)
      - Baltimore (Folder 6)
      - Boston (Folder 7)
      - Chicago (Box 93., Folder 1)
      - Indianapolis (Folder 2)
      - Jewish religious groups (Folder 3)
      - Local Committee Division (letters of the chairman) (Folder 4)
      - Massachusetts (Folder 5-6)
      - National Committee (Folder 7)
      - Philadelphia (Box 94., Folder 1)
      - United States. Congress (Folder 2)
    - Mailing lists (Folder 3)
    - Radio scripts (Folder 4)
    - Resolutions and statements
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Drafts (Folder 6)
      - Medical statement (Folder 7)
      - Women's statement (Folder 8)
    - Speakers' bureau file. See also SPEAKERS' BUREAU
    - Staff file
      - General
        - Instructions to fieldmen (Box 95., Folder 1-2)
        - Material for speakers (Folder 3)
      - Aydelott, George (Folder 4)
    - Miscellany (Folder 5)
  - Kershner, Howard, 1943-1946
    - Biographical material
      - Biographical sketches. Typescript and handwritten (Box 96., Folder 1)
      - Publicity. Printed and typescript material publicizing Kershner's national tour (Folder 2)
      - Speaking schedule. Typescript, mimeographed and handwritten notes on Kershner's speaking engagements during national tour (Folder 3)
      - Speaking tour report by cities. Excerpts from letters relating to Kershner's lectures, and itinerary (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1943
      - General. Relates to lecture tour
        - Arizona (Folder 5)
        - California (Folder 6)
        - Colorado (Folder 7)
        - Connecticut (Folder 8)
        - Florida (Folder 9)
        - Illinois (Folder 10)
        - Indiana (Folder 11)
        - Iowa (Folder 12)
        - Kansas (Folder 13)
        - Maryland (Folder 14)
        - Massachusetts (Folder 15)
        - Michigan (Folder 16)
        - Minnesota (Folder 17)
        - Missouri (Folder 18)
        - Nebraska (Folder 19)
        - New Hampshire (Folder 20)
        - New Jersey (Folder 21)
        - New York (Box 97., Folder 1)
        - North Carolina (Folder 2)
        - Ohio (Folder 3)
        - Oklahoma (Folder 4)
        - Oregon (Folder 5)
        - Pennsylvania (Folder 6)
        - Rhode Island (Folder 7)
        - Texas (Folder 8)
        - Utah (Folder 9)
        - Washington, D.C. (Folder 10)
        - Washington (Folder 11)
        - Wisconsin (Folder 12)
        - Wyoming (Folder 13)
      - Bloom, Sol (Folder 14)
      - The Christian Science Monitor (Folder 15)
      - Clarkson, Helen (Folder 16)
      - Fortune (Folder 17)
      - France, Edward (Folder 18)
      - Galpin, Perrin (Box 98., Folder 1)
      - Harper's Bazaar (Folder 2)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 3)
      - National Information Bureau (Folder 4)
      - Pye, Edith (Folder 5)
      - Saturday Evening Post (Folder 6)
    - Speeches and writings
      - "Incredible Folly of Starving Our Friends," speech, n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
      - One Humanity. Correspondence and memoranda (Folder 8)
      - "Schoolchildren in France, Hunger and Apathy, "London Times Educational Supplement, 1943 January 30. Includes printed article and related editorial (Folder 9)
      - Untitled, 1943 March 8 (Folder 10)
      - "Children Abroad Starving," New York Times, 1943 April 20. Includes printed copies, reprints and related correspondence (Folder 11)
      - "What Must Be Done to Start Relief," 1943 May 3. Mimeographed copy (Folder 12)
      - Introduction to Herbert Hoover, Carnegie Hall, 1943 May 8 (Folder 13)
      - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1943 May. Typescript and related clipping (Folder 14)
      - "We Starve Our Friends," Collier's, 1943 July 31. Reprint and related clipping (Folder 15)
      - "How to Save the Starving Children of Europe Without Aiding the Enemy," speech, 1943 September 25. Printed and mimeograph copies (Folder 16)
      - "American and British Public OpinionFavor Child Feeding in Nazi Dominated Countries," report to U.S. Congress. Mimeograph copies, press releases and clippings (Folder 17)
      - "Statement of Dr. Howard E. Kershner," U.S. Senate, Committee on Foreign Relations, Subcommittee on Relief for Starving Peoples of Europe, 1943 November. Printed copy and related clippings (Folder 18)
      - "Strategy and Humanity of Rescuing the Dying Children of Europe," 1943 November 11. (Folder 19)
      - "Who Blocks Feeding Europe?" The Commonweal, 1943 December 10. Printed copy (Folder 20)
      - "Food for Europe," The Reviewing Stand, a radio discussion with Wayne Taylor, Howard Kershner, et al., 1944 February 13. Printed copy (Folder 21)
      - "A Plea for the Children in Nazi Dominated Europe," a radio discussion by Senator Elbert D. Thomas, Senator Robert Taft, and Dr. Howard E. Kershner, 1944 March 3. Printed copies (Folder 22)
      - "Save Europe's Children: It's Your Move Mr. President," 1944 April 19. Reprints and mimeographed copies (Folder 23)